# Alexandru Cambose



alexcambose@yahoo.com



linkedin.com/in/alexcambose



http://alexcambose.com/

## **Summary**

With over 6 years of hands-on experience in software engineering, I've taken on diverse roles ranging from frontend developer, backend developer, mentor, and architect. I have a relentless drive to address intricate challenges in sectors like finance, web3, and blockchain.

#### # What I've Achieved

- Successfully developed, launched, and maintained, numerous projects from scratch, overseeing both back-end and front-end areas.
- Expertise in front-end development including TypeScript/JavaScript, React, Next.js, Redux, and more. I also have an eye for UI/UX design to ensure optimal user experiences.
- Backend-wise, I've delved deep from Node.js to advanced frameworks like Nest.js, Microservices, load balancing, Redis, Kafka, and more, enhancing application speed, performance, and reliability.
- Acquired comprehensive experience in Web3 technology, with a strong foundation in blockchain concepts, decentralized applications (dApps), smart contracts, and integrating blockchain systems with traditional web technologies.

#### # Tech Stack

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Next.js, Redux, Webpack, SCSS, Styled Components, Tailwind CSS, and more.
- Backend: Node.js, NestJS, Express, PostgreSQL, AWS, Redis, Kafka, GraphQL, and more.
- Blockchain: Web3, Ethers, Web3.js, Wagmi, Web3React, WalletconnectV2, Solidity, Geth.
- Mobile: React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Expo.

## **Experience**



## Senior Full-Stack Dapp Engineer

### Stealth Startup

Sep 2021 - Aug 2023 (2 years)

Worked on different projects over time, DeFi crypto options exchange, DeFi option-based yield generation app, ERC 4337 based DeFi price prediction app using spreads and digital options.

### Key Responsibilities:

- lead frontend developer
- worked on diverse roles, frontend, backend, and mobile
- developed custom packages to share functionality across apps and platforms, such as statemanagement, authentication, smart contract interactions and more
- developed custom backend core packages to abstract and reuse functionality across services
- integrated different authentication methods, injected wallet, Walletconnect V2, private key, for both web and mobile platforms
- implemented an option-based RFQ system to connect different entities with our product, achieved performant quoting via Redis, Kafka, and Websockets
- integrated bridge aggregators to be able to bridge assets to our chain
- developed custom charting solutions to display complex data such as option payouts and users trades

- conducted code reviews to ensure high code quality
- worked closely with the CEO to prioritize features and improvements
- conducted interviews for new candidates
- provided mentorship and guidance to developers

## Senior Full-Stack Engineer

### Instantoption

Nov 2020 - Feb 2021 (4 months)

Worked on a decentralized binary options protocol.

Key Responsibilities:

- led the frontend and backend development
- achieved seamless integration between frontend and on-chain smart contracts
- developed custom charting solutions
- implemented different authentication methods, both injected wallet and social login
- setup the infrastructure and ci/cd pipelines
- conducted code reviews to ensure high code standards

## Senior Full-Stack Engineer

#### **MixDice**

Oct 2018 - Jun 2020 (1 year 9 months)

Lead Developer for a cryptocurrency-based gaming platform.

Key Responsibilities:

- led the development of the project
- responsible for front-end and back-end web development
- conducted code reviews for team members to ensure high code quality
- setup the infrastructure and ci/cd pipelines for the app
- implemented Bitcoin and Ethereum deposit/withdrawal/wallet systems for users and administrators by setting up BCoin nodes (https://bcoin.io/) and Geth nodes (https://geth.ethereum.org/)
- implemented a provably fair random generation system (https://medium.com/@alexcambose/provably-fair-system-in-javascript-6457e028d2aa)
- implemented real-time websocket based communication for different parts of the app

## Fullstack Developer

### **Cult of Coders**

Sep 2018 - Oct 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Worked on different outsourcing projects and companies, including a US startup.

- responsible for front-end and back-end web development
- closely worked with clients in a scrum environment to establish objectives and deliver incremental software updates
- collaborate with the rest of the engineering team to design and launch new features
- setup and manage development and production servers to ensure a good workflow and stability Technologies:
- Javascript, React, SASS
- AWS, NodeJs, GraphQL, PostgreSQL

### **Education**

## Universitatea "Alexandru Ioan Cuza" din Iaşi

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

2018 - 2021

During university years, I have been studying about:

Data structures and algorithms, Web Technologies, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Networks, Database Modelling and Management Systems, Information, Security, Programming in C++, Software Engineering, Object-Oriented Programming exemplified in C++, Java, JavaScript, OpenGL programming and algorithms

## National College Garabet Ibraileanu lasi

High School Diploma, Mathematics and Computer Science 2014 - 2018

Computer science focused classes.

### **Skills**

Software Development • Victory • Highcharts • Ethers • NextJS • Ethereum • Web3.js • Express.js • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • GraphQL

### **Honors & Awards**

First place in the 24 hours Fii Practic Hackathon - Fii Practic - ASII

Apr 2018

https://fiipractic.asii.ro/

Opening Opportunities - https://www.openingopportunities.ro/

Won fourth place out of 51 projects in the Opening Opportunities contest and traveled to Bucharest to present the project in front of an audience.